William Langner Papers
William Langner Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Department of Education
    - America 2000, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Briefs (Box 57)
    - "Building effective program linkages" conference, 1990-1992; 7 folders (Box 57, 58, 59)
    - Goals 2000 (Box 59)
    - Goals and objectives (for others) (Box 59)
    - Help requests (Box 59)
    - Help requests - replies (Box 59)
    - Job descriptions and evaluations, 1980-1981 (Box 59)
    - Job descriptions and evaluations, 1982-1994; undated; 4 folders (Box 60)
    - "LD newsletter" (Box 60)
    - National Symposium on Adult Secondary Education, 1984-1989 (Box 60)
    - OVAE/OSERS joint conference, See "Building effective program linkages" conference.
    - Printed material, See Printed material: Department of Education.
    - "Travel folder", 1981-1983 (Box 61)
    - "Univ. & colleges" (Box 61)
    - "Workplace / family literacy programs -- Midwest" (Box 61)
    - Workshop evaluations (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 3 folders (Box 62)
  - Department of Justice (Box 62)
  - Distance Education Training Council (DETC), See National Home Study Council (NHSC).
  - Dolff, Helmuth (Box 63)
  - Dore, Daniel (Box 63)
  - Dyslexia Research Institute, See Hardman, Patricia K..
  - Easter Seal Society, includes National and Virginia branches (Box 63)
  - Educational Development Center, See Langner Learning Center.
  - Engleman, Vance (Box 63)
  - External Diploma Program, 3 folders (Box 63)
  - Federal Task Force on Disabled Persons (FTFDP) (Box 64)
  - Feldman, Marvin (president of Fashion Institute of Technology) (Box 64)
  - First National Conference for Adults with Special Learning Needs, See National Association for Adults with Special Learning Needs (NAASLN).
  - First National Congress for Adult Learners with Disabilities, See National Association for Adults with Special Learning Needs (NAASLN).
  - Florida Department of Education (Box 64)
  - Foster, Barbara (Box 64)
  - Fountain Square Publishing (Box 64)
  - Futurism / Futurists (Box 64)
  - Galaxy II Conference (Box 64)
  - Gallaudet University, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - GED Advisory Committee
    - Meeting minutes, 1976-1979 (Box 64)
    - Meeting minutes, 1981-1982; 3 folders (Box 64)
    - Meeting minutes, 1983-1987; 7 folders (Box 65)
    - Meeting minutes, 1988-1990; 7 folders (Box 66)
    - Meeting minutes, 1990-1992; 7 folders (Box 67)
    - Meeting minutes, 1992-1995; undated; 7 folders (Box 68)
  - Geisel, Ritchie (president of Recording for the Blind) (Box 68)
  - Genocide (Box 68)
  - George Washington University (Box 68)
  - Georgia Association for Children with Learning Disabilities (GACLD) (Box 68)
  - Goodwill Industries of America, 3 folders (Box 68, 69)
  - Gorman, Thomas (Box 69)
  - Greensboro Massacre (Box 69)
  - Grefe, Mary (Box 69)
  - Gross, Marsha (Box 69)
  - Gross, Ron, See also Learning Resources Network (LERN) (Gross was editor of LERN's newsletters). (Box 69)
  - Hadley School for the Blind (Box 69)
  - Hardman, Patricia K. (Box 69)
  - Hartley, Robert, Manuscript for book, With Wings as Eagles; 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Hawking, James (Box 69)
  - Heath Resource Center, project of the American Association of Higher Education; 5 folders (Box 70)
  - Hunsaker, Herbert, flier for "Dr. Hunsaker's Oriental Adventures" tour (Box 70)
  - IBM (Box 70)
  - IBM, material from their National Support Center for Persons with Disabilities (Box 71)
  - Information Services Inc. (Box 71)
  - Institute for the Management of Lifelong Education (IMLE) (Box 71)
  - Institute for the Study of Adult Literacy, includes 1 folder of "Mosaic" newsletter; 3 folders (Box 72)
  - International Association for Continuing Education and Training (IACET) (Box 72)
  - International Center for the Disabled, 1996 (Box 72)
  - International Conference on Adults with Disabilities, 1st, planning materials for (Box 72)
  - International Congress of University Adult Education (ICUAE) (Box 73)
  - International Council for Adult Education (ICAE)
    - Annual meetings
      - Annual meetings, 1975; 1976; 2 folders (Box 73)
      - Annual meetings, 1981-1982; 1984-1986,; 1988,; 1990; 8 folders (Box 74)
      - Annual meetings, 1994; 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1998; undated; 4 folders (Box 76)
    - Directories, 2 folders (Box 76, 77)
    - International Network for Adult Learners with Disabilities (Box 77)
    - Langner's notes (Box 77)
    - Meeting minutes (Box 77)
    - Newsletters
      - A-Z by title, includes "ICAE News," "International Associates Newsletter," "News from the Secretariat," "Pachamama," and "Panorama"; 5 folders (Box 77)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
    - Publication lists and bibliographies (Box 78)
    - Published material, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Women's programme (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
  - International Development Conference (Box 78)
  - International Platform Association (Box 78)
  - International Reading Association (IRA) (Box 79)
  - International Year of Disabled Persons (IYDP), 1981; 4 folders (Box 79)
  - Irlen Clinic (Box 79)
  - Jacques, Joseph (Box 80)
  - Ji Woong Cheong (Box 80)
  - Jordan, Dale (Box 80)
    See also LEAD 2000.
  - Joseph P. Kennedy Foundation (Box 80)
  - Jossey-Bass (Box 80)
  - Jurmo, Paul (Box 80)
  - Kansas State University (Box 80)
  - Keller, Helen (Box 80)
  - Kempfer, Homer (Box 80)
    See also Continuing Education Council (CEC).
  - Kidder, Carolyn Buell (Box 80)
  - Kirschner Associates (Box 80)
  - Knowles, Malcolm (Box 80)
  - Koloski, Judy (Box 80)
    See also National Adult Education Professional Development Consortium (NAEPDC).
  - Kulich, Jindra (Box 80)
  - Kurland, Norman (Box 80)
    See also Study Circles Consortium.
  - Lab School of Washington (Box 80)
    See also Multimedia: Falling Through the Cracks: Learning Disabled Adults Speak Out (Box 162).
  - Landmark College (Box 80)
  - Landmark School, ca. 1977-1981 (Box 80)
  - Langner and Associates, circa 1951-1963; 1974-1976?; Langner's educational consulting service; 6 folders (Box 81)
  - Langner and Company, Langner's import/export business; 5 folders (Box 81, 82)
  - Langner Foundation, Langner's non-profit, provided scholarships to Langner Learning Center (Box 82)
  - Langner Learning Center
    Langner Learning Center (LLC) was the last of a series of educational institutions owned and operated by William Langner. The first, Commonwealth Tutoring, was formed in 1964. This evolved into the Educational Development Center (EDC) sometime around 1966, which in turn became Langner Learning Center in 1970. At various times, these organizations also comprised the Academic Bookstore, the Handy Craft Shop, and translation services. Since the organizations overlapped both chronologically and financially, material from all of these ventures is contained in this series.
    - Correspondence
      - [General], 1965-1966; 3 folders (Box 82)
      - [General], 1966-1970; 7 folders (Box 83)
      - [General], 1970-1971; 6 folders (Box 84)
      - [General], 1971-1972; 5 folders (Box 85)
      - [General], 1972-1973; 5 folders (Box 86)
      - [General], 1973-1978; 8 folders (Box 87)
      - [General], 1979-1987; 4 folders (Box 88)
      - [General], undated; 6 folders (Box 88, 89)
    - Clippings, press releases (Box 89)
    - Forms (Box 89)
    - Ryan, Mary Ann, research paper on LLC (Box 89)
    - Student folder (sample) (Box 89)
    - Tax exemption application, 1962 (Box 162)
    - Transcripts of meetings and conferences (Box 90)
  - Langner Learning Systems (Box 90)
  - Laubach Literacy, includes "Literacy Advance" and other newsletters (Box 90)
  - LEAD 2000 (Box 90)
  - Learning Disabilities Association (LDA), includes 1 folder of "LDA Newsbriefs" newsletters; 2 folders (Box 90)
  - Learning Disabilities Council (Box 90)
  - Learning Press International (Box 90)
  - Learning Resources Network (LERN), includes many issues of "Adult and Continuing Education Today," "Learning Connection," "Adult Learning Review," "Course Trends in Adult Learning," "Marketing Adult Education" and other newsletters; 6 folders (Box 90, 91)
  - Learning Styles Network (Box 91)
  - Lek, Sambonn (Box 91)
  - Lindamood-Bell Learning Process (Box 91)
    See also Multimedia: Lindamood-Bell Learning Processes / Learning Disabilities Association Conference / by Nanci Bell (Box 162).
  - Literacy Volunteers of America (LVA), includes 1 folder of newsletters ("The Reader," "Literacy Practitioner"); 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Liveright, Alexander (Box 92)
  - Macomber, Janet (Box 92)
  - Margaret Sanger Center (Box 92)
  - Maryland Association for Adult Community Continuing Education (MAACCE) (Box 92)
  - McGraw, Harold W. (Box 92)
  - Metropolitan Washington Association for Adult and Continuing Education (MWAACE), 2 folders (Box 92)
  - Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments (Box 92)
  - Miami Project to Cure Paralysis (Box 92)
  - Michaux, Louis (Box 92)
  - Michigan Association for Adult and Continuing Education (Box 92)
  - Mid-Atlantic Center for Community Education (MACCE), 2 folders (Box 92, 93)
  - Missouri Valley Adult Education Association (Box 93)
  - Montclair State College, includes "Adult Education Clearinghouse Newsletter"; 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Mulcrone, Patricia, includes "Model for Workplace Literacy" from her dissertation (Box 93)
  - Nardini, Joe (Box 93)
  - National Adult Education Professional Development Clearinghouse (NAEPDC), includes "StateLine" newsletter; 2 folders (Box 93)
  - National Adult Literacy and Learning Disability Center (NALLDC), includes draft of NALLDC Toolkit, "Linkages" newsletter, other publications; 4 folders (Box 93, 94)
  - National Advisory Council on Adult Education (NACAE)
    - Correspondence
      - [General], 1969; 1971; 4 folders (Box 94)
      - [General], 1973-1975 (Box 94)
      - [General], 1975-1976; 5 folders (Box 95)
      - [General], 1977-1980 (Box 96)
      - [General], 1982-1985; 1987 (Box 96)
      - [General], undated (Box 96)
    - Activity and information reports, 1973-1976 (Box 96)
    - Annual reports, 1968; 1972-1974,; 1976-1977,; 1978-1983,; 1985; 4 folders (Box 96)
    - Council handbook (Box 97)
    - Minutes, 1973-1975; 4 folders (Box 97)
    - Minutes, 1975-1976; 4 folders (Box 98)
    - Printed material, 2 folders (Box 98)
    - Program visitation reports (Box 98)
    - Reports, papers, other writings, 6 folders (Box 98, 99, 100)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 100)
  - National Advisory Council on Indian Education, includes 15th (1988) and 16th (1989) reports to Congress; 2 folders (Box 100)
  - National Advisory Council on Vocational Education (Box 100)
  - National Association for Adults with Special Learning Needs (NAASLN)
    - Correspondence
      - [General], 1987 (Box 100)
      - [General], 1987-1990; 6 folders (Box 101)
      - [General], 1990-1992; 6 folders (Box 102)
      - [General], 1993-1998; 7 folders (Box 103)
      - [General], undated; 3 folders (Box 103, 104)
    - Bylaws, articles of incorporation, constitution (Box 104)
    - Clippings about (Box 104)
    - Conferences
      - Conferences, 1988-1991; 4 folders (Box 104)
      - Conferences, 1992; 1994,; 1996,; 1997; 4 folders (Box 105)
    - Printed material
      - Journal of NAASLN, 1991-1994; 4 issues (Box 106)
      - Newsletter (Box 106)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 106)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 106)
  - National Association for Public and Continuing Education (NAPCAE), includes almanacs and "Pulse of public continuing and adult education" newsletters; 5 folders (Box 106)
  - National Association for Public and Continuing Education (NAPCAE), includes "Techniques for teachers of adults" newsletters (Box 107)
  - National Association of Rehabilitation Facilities (NARF) (Box 107)
  - National Center on Adult Literacy (NCAL), includes "NCAL Connections" newsletters; 3 folders (Box 107)
  - National Center for Community Education (Box 107)
  - National Center for Disability Services (Box 107)
  - National Center for Family Literacy, includes "National Center for Family Literacy" newsletter; 2 folders (Box 107)
  - National Center for Learning Disabilities (Box 107)
  - National Center for Research in Vocational Education (NCRVE), includes "CenterGram," "Change Agent," "InterChange," "TASPP Bulletin" and other newsletters; 4 folders (Box 108)
  - National Coalition for Literacy (Box 108)
  - National Community Education Association (NCEA) (Box 108)
  - National Council on Disability (Box 108)
  - National Council on the Handicapped, See National Council on Disability.
  - National Council of La Raza (Box 109)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 109)
  - National Home Study Council (NHSC), includes "NHSC News," "Bulletin," and "NHSC Report" newsletters, and two reports: "Predicting Distance Education in the Year 2001 Final Report" (1982) and "New Course Planning" (1989); 3 folders (Box 109)
  - National Indian Adult Education Association (Box 109)
  - National Information Center for Handicapped Children and Youth (NICHCY) (Box 109)
  - National Institute on Disability and Rehabilitation Research (NIDRR)
    - Correspondence (Box 109)
    - Newsletters, includes "Disability Abstracts" and "Rehab Brief" newsletters (Box 109)
    - Program directories, 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 110)
  - National Institute for Literacy, includes "Literacy News" and "Policy Update" newsletters; 2 folders (Box 111)
  - National Learning Laboratory (Box 111)
  - National Network of Learning Disabled Adults (Box 111)
  - National Organization on Disability (NOD), includes "NOD Report" and "NOD Update" newsletters; 2 folders (Box 111)
  - National Public Radio (NPR) (Box 111)
  - National Rehabilitation Association (Box 111)
  - National Rehabilitation Facilities Coalition (NRFC) (Box 111)
  - National Rehabilitation Information Center (NARIC), includes "NARIC Quarterly" newsletter; 3 folders (Box 111, 112)
  - National Rural Development Institute (Box 112)
  - National Rural and Small Schools Consortium (Box 112)
  - National Spinal Cord Injury Hotline (Box 112)
  - National Task Force on Disability (NTFD) (Box 112)
  - National University Continuing Education Association (NUCEA) (Box 112)
  - National Workplace Literacy Project (Box 112)
  - Native Americans, 2 folders; See also National Advisory Council on Indian Education. (Box 112)
  - New Jersey Association for Lifelong Learning (NJALL) (Box 112)
  - NORCECA (North, Central America and Caribbean) (Box 113)
  - North Dakota Department of Public Instruction, Adult Education program review, 3 folders (Box 113)
  - Northern Illinois University (Box 113)
  - Office on Educational Credit and Credentials (Box 113)
  - Ohio State University (Box 113)
    See also National Center for Research in Vocational Education (NCRVE).
  - Oklahoma State University (Box 113)
  - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education (OISE), Africa study tour (Box 113)
  - Optometric Extension Program (Box 113)
  - Orton Dyslexia Society (Box 113)
  - Pan American Development Foundation (Box 113)
  - Partners of the Americas (Box 113)
  - Patton, Jim (Box 113)
  - Pennsylvania Association for Adult and Continuing Education (PAACE) (Box 113)
  - Perceptual Dynamics (Box 114)
  - Plum, Kenneth R., speech from 24th Annual Conference of Adult Education Association of Virginia (Box 114)
  - President's Committee on Employment of People with Disabilities, 3 folders (Box 114)
  - President's Committee on Mental Retardation, 2 folders (Box 114)
  - President's Task Force on Private Sector Initiatives (Box 114)
  - Project CLEAR, 2 folders (Box 114, 115)
  - Project Literacy US (PLUS), 2 folders (Box 115)
  - Public Broadcasting System (PBS) (Box 115)
  - Rankin, Jeanette (Box 115)
  - Reagan, Ronald (Box 115)
  - Rebus Institute (Box 115)
  - Rehabilitative Engineering and Assistive Technology Society of North America (RESNA) (Box 115)
  - Republican party, 2 folders (Box 115)
  - Resumes (of others) (Box 116)
  - Richmond Area Reading Council (Box 116)
  - Richmond Area Rehabilitation Center (Box 116)
  - Richmond First Club (Box 116)
  - Richmond Mayor's Committee on the Handicapped (Box 116)
  - Richmond Public Schools (Box 116)
  - Rivera, William (Box 116)
  - Roberts, Paul E. (Box 116)
  - Robson, R. Anthony (Box 116)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT) (Box 116)
  - Royce, Sherry, See Adult Basic and Literacy Education (ABLE) of Pennsylvania.
  - Scott, Foresman and Company (Box 116)
  - Siddiqui, Dilnawaz (Box 116)
  - Siwisa, Dennis (Box 116)
  - Smoak, Tom and Betsy (Box 116)
  - Society for International Development (SID) (Box 116)
  - South East Regional Resource Center (Box 116)
  - SpecTrans (Box 116)
  - Stambler, Moses, article on adult educators' visit to India (Box 116)
  - Steck-Vaughn Company, includes "Directions" newsletter (Box 116, 117)
  - Stern Center for Language and Learning, includes "Teaching adults with learning disabilities: Study guide" (Box 117)
  - Study Circle Consortium (Box 117)
  - Study Circles Resource Center, includes "Focus on Study Circles" newsletter; 3 folders (Box 117)
  - Survival International USA (Box 118)
  - Syracuse University, includes "CREA-tivity in New York" newsletter; 2 folders (Box 118)
  - Talbot, Walter D., speech given at 2d International Community Education Conference (Box 118)
  - TASH (The Association for Persons with Severe Handicaps) (Box 118)
  - Teacher's College, Columbia University, includes transcript of Langner's speech at 1991 conference on literacy and adults with severe learning difficulties; 2 folders (Box 118)
  - Technical Assistance for Special Populations Program (TASPP), See National Center for Research in Vocational Education (NCRVE).
  - Tronstad, Barry (Box 118)
  - Travis, George Y. (Box 118)
  - U.N. Decade of Disabled Persons, See International Year of Disabled Persons.
  - UNESCO, includes reports, papers, and many issues of "Adult education Information notes" newsletter; 5 folders (Box 118, 119)
  - University of the District of Columbia (Box 119)
  - University of Kansas (Box 119)
  - University of Missouri-St. Louis (Box 119)
  - University of New England (Australia) (Box 119)
  - University of Virginia (Box 119)
  - University Without Walls (Box 119)
  - Virginia Adult Institute for Lifelong Learning (VAILL) (Box 119)
  - Virginia Association for Adult and Continuing Education (VAACE) (Box 119)
  - Virginia Association of Independent Special Education Facilities (VAISEF) (Box 120)
  - Virginia Association of Rehabilitation Facilities (Box 120)
  - Virginia, Commonwealth of
    - Board of Education/Department of Education (Box 120)
    - Department of Rehabilitative Services (Box 120)
    - Department of Vocational Rehabilitation, includes "Challenge" newsletter; 4 folders (Box 120)
    - Governor's Committee on the Employment of the Handicapped (Box 120)
    - Governor's Study Commission on Vocational Rehabilitation, includes 2-volume published report; 2 folders (Box 121)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 121)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University
    - Correspondence, 1969-1978; 3 folders (Box 121)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1980; 1983,; 1985,; 1988-1990,; 1993 (Box 122)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 122)
    - Printed material (Box 122)
    - RES-301E, taught by Langner; 2 folders (Box 122)
    - Syllabi (Box 122)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Box 122)
  - Virginia State University (Box 122)
  - Wallingford Adult Education (Box 122)
  - Warner, John (Box 122)
  - Washington State University (Box 122)
  - Westberry, Susan (Box 122)
  - Wilson Learning Center (Barbara and Ed Wilson) (Box 123)
  - Wingspread Conference (Box 123)
  - "With Wings as Eagles", See Hartley, Robert.
  - Wolfbein, Seymour L. (Box 123)
  - Woodland Hall Academy, See Hardman, Patricia K..
  - Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center (Box 123)
  - Zaba, Joel (Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 125)
  - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 126)
- Memorabilia
  - Certificates (Box 127)
  - Clippings about (Box 127)
  - Commemorative paperweights (Box 162)
  - Guest book (Box 162)
  - Letters of appreciation/thanks (Box 127)
  - Maps, Caribbean and West Indies (Box 162)
  - Nameplate (Box 162)
  - Passports (Box 127)
  - Photographs of Langner (Box 127)
  - Photographs of others (Box 127)
  - Postcards (Box 162)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 127)
- Multimedia
  - "Bill's distance learning course files", 2/24/89; langner_008; handwritten label, appears to be Langner's personal files; 1 floppy disk, 5-1/4" (Box 162)
  - Business Package #1 / Reports / Supervisor / Outbound Telemarketing / Outside Sales / Profiles, International, circa 1987; langner_005; 1 floppy disk, 5-1/4" (Box 162)
  - Falling Through the Cracks: Learning Disabled Adults Speak Out / The Lab School of Washington, 1985; langner_002; 1 audiocassette (Box 162)
  - Graduating to Independence / Social Security Administration Office of Disability, langner_018 to langner_020; includes cover letter, packet of supporting material; in binder, as originally published/distributed; 1 videocassette; 2 floppy discs 5-1/4" (Box 162)
  - Lindamood-Bell Learning Processes / Learning Disabilities Association Conference / by Nanci Bell, undated; langner_001; 1 audiocassette (Box 162)
  - MS-Kermit program disk and documnetation [sic] version 2.31 / Syracuse University Academic Computing Services, 16 Jun 1988; langner_004; 1 floppy disk, 5-1/4" (Box 162)
  - National Center on Adult Literacy Publications, Volume IV / Should Reading-Disabled Adults be Distinguished from Other Adults Seeking Reading Instruction? (TR93-7) / Prison Literacy: Implications for Program and Assessment Policy (TR93-1) / National Center on Adult Literacy, 1984; langner_003; 1 floppy disk, 5-1/4", "WordPerfect 5.0 for IBM Compatible" (Box 162)
  - The PROFILE / Profiles, International / Product: Introduction Package / Reports: 2, circa 1987; langner_006; handwritten post-it attached, "Complete and return for a complimentary profile, verbal and written"; 1 floppy disk, 5-1/4" (Box 162)
  - Reading - Level 1, Lessons 1- 14, 19 and 22 / Warren Foundation Turning Point Curriculum - English Communication for the World, 1981; langner_010 through langner_017; in vinyl case printed with title, Warren Foundation logo, as sold/distributed; 8 audiocassettes (Box 162)
  - Strategies for Teaching Adults with Learning Difficulties, 1986[?]; langner_009; videotape, "STALD TEST PTS. I AND II"; order form, informational booklet, scoring sheets, and final report "Strategies for Teaching Adults with Learning Difficulties"; in vinyl case as originally distributed/sold; 1 audiocassette (Box 162)
  - [untitled], langner_007; blank label, contents unknown; 1 floppy disk, 5-1/4" (Box 162)
- Printed material, in Hollinger cartons, very heavy
  - Adult Basic Education (ABE), 2 boxes + 5 folders (Box 128, 129, 130)
  - Adult Education Act, 4 folders (Box 130)
  - Americans with Disabilities Act (Box 131)
  - Conferences, 6 folders (Box 132)
  - Competency-based adult education, 4 folders (Box 133)
  - Correctional education, 10 folders (Box 133)
  - Department of Education
    - Clearinghouse of adult education and literacy, briefs, fact sheets, reports, bibliographies, directories, papers, etc (Box 134)
    - Newsletters, 22 folders (Box 135)
    - Reports and papers, 1964; 1970-1990; 18 folders (Box 136)
    - Reports and papers, 1991-1998; undated; 15 folders (Box 137)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 137)
  - GED (Box 138)
    See also Misc newsletters: G for several newsletters on the GED.
  - Independent study / distance learning, 9 folders (Box 130, 132)
  - International education (Box 139)
  - Learning disabled education, 3 folders + 4 boxes (Box 130, 140-143)
  - Literacy, 2 boxes (Box 144, 145)
  - Misc books (Box 146)